<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jay Hickey</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jayhickey.com/feeds/07.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jayhickey.com/</id><updated>2012-07-31T06:28:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Video Game Movies</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/07/video-game-movies" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-31T06:28:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-07-31:2012/07/video-game-movies</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I can't get enough of these "video game turned movie" posters. I especially like the &lt;em&gt;Portal&lt;/em&gt; one—nice subtle details. Story by Eddy Kitsis and Adam Horowitz (&lt;em&gt;Lost&lt;/em&gt; writers), Joseph Kosinski (of &lt;em&gt;TRON: Legacy&lt;/em&gt; fame) as the director, and of course starring Natalie Portman. Oh how happy I would be if this got made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://jayhickey.com/media/2012/07/portal-movie.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Portal Movie" src="http://jayhickey.com/media/2012/07/portal-movie-thumb.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Magnetic Fields to Improve Smartphone Location Accuracy</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/07/using-magnetic-fields-to-improve-location" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-17T05:44:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-07-17:2012/07/using-magnetic-fields-to-improve-location</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The technology is accurate to between 10 centimeters and two meters, uses your phone's compass, and &lt;em&gt;no upfront infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; is needed: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indoor Atlas's technology works by analyzing the magnetic field inside a building. The structure of a building causes disturbances to the Earth's magnetic field. Once these disturbances are mapped, people can be pinpointed within them through their phone's magnetometer. Indoor Atlas's product arose from research findings that showed the signature magnetic field within buildings was sufficiently varied and stable to be used for navigation, says company founder and computer science professor Janne Haverinen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this works as advertised, the possibilities are endless. An app could route you around a store based on your shopping list, automatically checking off the items as you go. Or let you find exactly where your friend is in a busy shopping mall. And businesses don't have to drop the dough to fill the place with WiFi or NFC antennas. I often use the excellent &lt;a href="http://aisle411.com/"&gt;aisle411&lt;/a&gt; app for in-store navigation at my local Kroger. But the lack of a "blue dot" showing my present location within in the store results in me staring too long at my phone, trying not to block the isle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would dramatically improve &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geo-fence"&gt;geofencing&lt;/a&gt; too. I constantly take advantage of the nearby contexts features of &lt;a href="http://www.omnigroup.com/products/omnifocus-iphone/"&gt;Omnifocus for iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, such as setting reminders for leaving or arriving at my work and home. It's also great for setting specific searches as locations, such as "Grocery Store" or "Walgreens" (I look forward to giving the just released, "iOS Reminders on streoids" app, &lt;a href="http://builtbysnowman.com/"&gt;Checkmark&lt;/a&gt;, a spin too). There's a constant vexation with this geofencing though. To save battery, it doesn't use full GPS. So it isn't accurate enough, especially indoors. I find myself only setting "arriving" reminders, because the "leaving" reminder to grab the package I need to take to FedEx doesn't end up going off until I'm already in my car and heading down the road. But add integration with this Indoor Atlas technology, and the alert could go off the second I step out the front door. We're at the tip of the iceberg when it comes to the potential of geofencing, and as a impressively forgetful person, I can't wait to see this take off.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Tweet Archiver</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/07/tweet-archiver" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-06T07:38:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-07-06:2012/07/tweet-archiver</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Super handy script by my buddy Tim Bueno. Grabs all of your past tweets (well, the last 3200) and whips them together into a nice plain text file. Chuck the text file from Tim's script into Dropbox, combine it with this &lt;a href="http://ifttt.com/recipes/37991"&gt;IFTTT Recipe&lt;/a&gt;, and everything new you tweet will be appended, keeping it up to date. Love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It never hurts to have a local backup of the digital information that matters to you. Especially when it's a free service you don't pay for, like Twitter. One day, everything might disappear.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Dubstep Dispute</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/07/dubstep-dispute" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-06T07:21:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-07-06:2012/07/dubstep-dispute</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Awesome animation in this video. And the droids look like they're from Star Wars, making it even better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/44878206?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ff0000&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&amp;amp;autoplay=0" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</summary></entry></feed>