<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jay Hickey</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jayhickey.com/feeds/11.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jayhickey.com/</id><updated>2012-11-26T10:11:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Product Desirability = Profitability</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/11/product-desirability-profitability" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-26T10:11:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-11-26:2012/11/product-desirability-profitability</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fascinating article on how the VW Group has become so successful. Craziest part—the company employs 310,000 more people, built 200,000 fewer vehicles in 2012, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; recorded $3.1 billion more in profits this year than General Motors.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Best Way to Spend Thanksgiving</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/11/the-best-way-to-spend-thanksgiving" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-22T02:36:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-11-22:2012/11/the-best-way-to-spend-thanksgiving</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The best way to spend Thanksgiving" src="http://jayhickey.com/media/instagram/2012-11-22_193447.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href="http://instagram.com"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Wireless for "Other" Electronics</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/11/wireless-for-other-electronics" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-14T11:03:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-11-14:2012/11/wireless-for-other-electronics</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Interesting post by Technology Review about French startup SigFox, and their new approach to creating a wireless network: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SigFox is focused on connecting cheap sensors and “dumb” home appliances to the Internet. The goal is to make all kinds of appliances and infrastructure, from power grids to microwave ovens, smarter by letting them share data. The general concept, known as “the Internet of Things,” has been discussed in academic circles for years, but it has yet to come to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is, without a doubt, a service I see on the horizon. I wouldn't be surprised to see a similar infrastructure start up in the U.S. very soon. SigFox is already about to go live in France. With how dumb and greedy all of the cellular carriers are, it's very unlikely any of them will cost-effectively fill the (on the rise) wireless appliance market. Plus SigFox' solution is cheaper, provides much lower energy consumption, and operates over a much longer range:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A conventional cellular connection consumes 5,000 microwatts, but a two-way SigFox connection uses just 100. The company also says it is close to rolling out a network to the whole of France—an area larger than California—using just 1,000 antennas. Deployments are beginning in other European countries, and discussions are under way with U.S.-based cellular carriers about teaming up to roll out its technology stateside, says Nicholls. “SigFox can cover the entire U.S. territory with around 10,000 gateways, whereas a traditional cellular network operator needs at least several hundred thousand,” he says. This should make deployment significantly faster, and cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost is further reduced thanks to their use of license-free frequency spectrum. SigFox thinks it should be possible to charge a fee of around $1 a year per device&lt;sup id="fnref:dollar"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:dollar" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The downside, of course, is the extremely low bandwidth of 100 bits/s. But for most devices, that doesn't matter. SigFox mentions potential applications ranging from Internet-connected bathroom scales to electrical smart grids and parking lot monitoring. I'm very excited for the potential of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:dollar"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. &lt;em&gt;One dollar.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:dollar" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>How Pythonista Changed My Workflow</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/11/how-pythonista-changed-my-workflow" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-13T11:24:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-11-13:2012/11/how-pythonista-changed-my-workflow</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Massively awesome article by Federico Viticci on MacStories. Tons of handy scripts. I'm definitely adding both &lt;code&gt;formd.py&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Screenshots.py&lt;/code&gt; to my tool belt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had my eye on &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pythonista/id528579881?mt=8"&gt;Pythonista&lt;/a&gt; for a while, and finally purchased it last week when it updated to version 1.2. My only regret is that I didn't purchase it earlier. I've had so much fun writing scripts and automating tasks on my iPhone and iPad. I uploaded a few of my own to &lt;a href="https://github.com/jayhickey/Pythonista-Scripts"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for safekeeping, so feel free to check them out and take some ideas. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Wrong Name</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/11/the-wrong-name" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-13T03:15:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-11-13:2012/11/the-wrong-name</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Upsettingly astute article by Aaron Mahnke:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to call myself a Christian anymore. It would be deceptive to do that. No, I’m simply a practitioner of a two-thousand year old Jewish sect that believes in making the world a better place. It was founded by a man named Jesus and his teachings were so revolutionary, so countercultural, so anti-religion that his students simply called themselves Followers of the Way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love that description.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>3D Printed Aston Martin for Skyfall</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/11/skyfall-aston-martin" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-12T02:12:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-11-12:2012/11/skyfall-aston-martin</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;They didn't actually blow up an Aston Martin DB5 in Skyfall—it was just a 1/3 scale, extremely detailed, 3D printed model. Thank goodness.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Dark Sky plot for GeekTool</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/11/dark-sky-plot-for-geektool" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-09T05:48:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-11-09:2012/11/dark-sky-plot-for-geektool</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Drang has a great follow up to my &lt;a href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/10/bringing-dark-sky-to-the-mac-with-pysky"&gt;PySky post&lt;/a&gt;, with some info on creating a clean &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/geektool/id456877552?l=fr&amp;amp;ls=1&amp;amp;mt=12"&gt;GeekTool&lt;/a&gt; plot. I like the cleanliness of Drang's plot, and am probably going to eventually tweak mine to look similar. If you decide to put Dark Sky on your Desktop, make sure to also follow Dr. Drang's closing tip about getting rid of that pesky rocket icon. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>'Toy Story 3' &amp; 'Catching Fire' Writer Tapped for 'Star Wars: Episode VII'</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/11/toy-story-catching-fire-writer-tapped-for-star-wars-episode-vii" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-09T05:33:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-11-09:2012/11/toy-story-catching-fire-writer-tapped-for-star-wars-episode-vii</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looks like Disney is really trying to get the ball rolling on these &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; sequels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Arndt, the Oscar-winning writer behind &lt;em&gt;Toy Story 3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Hunger Games: Catching Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Little Miss Sunshine&lt;/em&gt; has been tapped by Disney and Lucasfilm to script &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;: Episode VII. The screenwriter has turned in a 40-to-50 page treatment for the long-anticipated sequel, but he might not be the only writer attached to the project by the time the film goes in front of cameras (but no other names have surfaced yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hadn't heard of Arndt until I read this article, but he sounds like a great choice. Both &lt;em&gt;Toy Story 3&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Little Miss Sunshine&lt;/em&gt; had phenomenal writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Lucasfilm has &lt;a href="http://starwars.com/news/michael-arndt-to-write-screenplay-for-star-wars-episode-vii.html"&gt;officially confirmed&lt;/a&gt; that Michael Arndt will write the screenplay for Episode VII. Exciting. I wonder how long it'll be before details about the plot start leaking out? &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Let's go Cincinnati!</title><link href="http://jayhickey.com/2012/11/let-s-go-cincinnati" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-03T01:44:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jay Hickey</name></author><id>tag:jayhickey.com,2012-11-03:2012/11/let-s-go-cincinnati</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Let's go Cincinnati!" src="http://jayhickey.com/media/instagram/2012-11-03_174407.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Via &lt;a href="http://instagram.com"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>